Ian Hinkle

As a Support Analyst, I have excelled in handling customer escalations and training new team members. My strong problem-solving skills and ability to adapt quickly to new technical challenges have also allowed me to learn and incorporate new tools and skills. In addition to my technical expertise, I have strong experience in customer service, wholesale and internal training, and retail operations, making me a well-rounded and reliable team member.

ianwhinkle@gmail.com

(512) 395-7507

Austin

linkedin.com/in/ianwhinkle

in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Analyst II MadCap Software, Inc.

04/2022 - Present

 Managed ticket delegation based on complexity and team member skills.

- Handled customer escalations and issues with increased urgency and complexity.
- Trained new team members on MadCap products and troubleshooting processes.
- Diagnosed and submitted over 90 unique software defect reports, including several which were high-priority or critical.

Technical Support Analyst I MadCap Software, Inc.

09/2020 - 04/2022

- Performed end-to-end troubleshooting involving interpretation, analysis, and research
- Communicated complex solutions and assisted end-users with the implementation.
- Proficient in MadCap AMS software suite and related integrations (Salesforce, Zendesk, ServiceNow).

06/2016 - 09/2020

- Responsible for education and technical training across three company locations with 15+ employees.
- Provided technical training and education for 15+ wholesale client businesses.
- Developed and taught coursework across multiple certification levels as an Authorized Specialty Coffee Association Trainer (PowerPoint, Word).
- Oversaw retail operations including staff management and product supply-chain management.
- Managed employee/guest interactions, provided welcoming customer service, and resolved guest complaints/service issues.
- Large reduction in product overhead through product stream optimization.
- Established and enforced rigorous quality control protocols and systems company-wide.

SOFT SKILLS

Customer Service Problem Solving Learning

Quick to Grasp Technical Skills Adaptable

Conflict Resolution

HARD SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Business WLAN installation (2019)

 Installed wireless access points. Configured and optimized traffic for internal business services and separate guest networks.

Developed Internal Product Supply Tracker

 I created a tracking spreadsheet with external forms for employee input to calculate usage trends for multiple SKUs.

Android Phone Modifications

- Customized and installed Android boot scripts to modify smartphone system settings and behaviors.
- Utilized Command-line tools (Android Debug Bridge) to flash custom firmware and acquire root-level permissions.

EDUCATION

Microbiology Major Texas State University

San Marcos, Texas

High School DiplomaLake Travis High School

Relevant Courses

 Computer Programming (Java, three years)